<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry Pi | George Litos</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/raspberry-pi/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tag/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Raspberry Pi</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 18:34:13 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hudd78b5bc2e9f708bbbb3651dc62e55b2_16066_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/raspberry-pi/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireguard: A Better VPN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/wireguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 18:34:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/wireguard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual Private Networks &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;(VPNs)&lt;/a&gt; are essential tools for protecting your online privacy and security. But traditional VPNs can sometimes be slow and bog down your connection. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; is a new, innovative VPN protocol that offers several advantages over traditional options, it has a cool logo too 😎.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WireGuard is much simpler and leaner than older VPN protocols. This means it&amp;rsquo;s faster and more efficient, using fewer resources and providing a smoother online experience. On top of that, WireGuard prioritizes strong security. It utilizes modern cryptographic techniques to keep your data safe and encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WireGuard is also easy to set up and use. It&amp;rsquo;s available on a wide range of platforms, including Linux, macOS, Windows, Android, and iOS. You can quickly configure WireGuard to connect to a VPN server and start protecting your online activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed Wireguard on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://dietpi.com/docs/software/vpn/#wireguard&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RPi4 powered by DietPi&lt;/a&gt; and connected to my selfhosted VPN server in just a few minutes on my Macbook Air and on my Android powered phone (Motorola G32). Check the available clients &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com/install/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, there is one for everyone, even iOS and FreeBSD!. The connection was fast and reliable, with minimal impact on my internet speed. I was impressed by how easy it was to use and how well it performed, I could access my UNRAID server and my Synology with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
